A. Detailed Introduction + Superfluous Information; B. Script Usage Method

A. I've been trying to set up a cloud server with friends for the past few days, and it took a long time but we finally got it done. However, I found the mod settings particularly challenging, especially when dealing with many mods. Let me explain this part in detail.

After setting up the cloud server, some classmates wanted to upload their own world (I won't go into details here, refer to other tutorials for that), and the mods required for that world. In the Document->klei->DontStarveTogether folder, there are 5 clusters (saves). Suppose you uploaded cluster 1, then the modoverriders.lua files in the master folder (main world) and caves folder (underground) of cluster 1 (save 1) contain all the mod configuration information for this save. Note that the modoverriders.lua files in both folders are the same.

On the cloud server, you will have a mods folder containing four document files, one of which is called dedicated_server_mods_setup.lua. It can be opened like a txt file, initially containing some basic information.

To run mods properly on the cloud server, this dedicated_server_mods_setup.lua must record the corresponding workshop id of the mod: It looks like this

ServerModSetup("488009136")
ServerModSetup("488018406")
ServerModSetup("648064643")

The problem is, it's very cumbersome to enter so many mod ids one by one. So, I wrote a script in C. It extracts the workshop mod ids used in the save from the modoverriders.lua and stores them in a new dedicated_server_mods_setup.lua.
Finally, just replace the old lua file with this new dedicated_server_mods_setup.lua.

B: Usage method,

Place the modsetup script and any modoverriders.lua from the save in the same directory (the desktop is fine), then open the terminal on Mac or press "Start+R" on Windows, then type cmd to call out the console (I don't remember the name).

Enter the script directory by typing cd, for example, typing cd Desktop in the terminal will take you to the desktop. If it fails, please enter LS to see the current directory and use cd + folder to enter the folder.

Finally, type ./modsetup (it's like this on Mac, should be the same on Windows), and a new dedicated_server_mods_setup.lua will be generated in the same directory, containing the workshop mod id required for the cloud server. Then upload this file to the same folder on the server and replace the old file with the same name.

If you have any questions about setting up mods, please leave a message. I won't be involved in other issues. Have fun playing!